等等
Wait.
-我们可没批准这张海报  -是啊
- We didn't approve this poster. - No.
是希德·罗斯批的  希德想怎么样就怎么样
Sid Ross did. And what Sid wants, Sid gets.
他才不管电视网的意见呢
He doesn't care what the network thinks.
那何必还跟他讨论卡司变动的事宜
Then what's the point of discussing cast changes with him?
反正他也会想做什么做什么
He's just gonna do what he wants regardless.
一向如此
As always.
他死了吗
Is he dead?!
Is he dead?
他死了吗
早啊  玛莎
Hey, good morning, Martha.
-他死了吗  -谁死了
- Is he dead? - Is who dead?
不  我是在...
No, I'm just...
他死了吗
Is he dead?
卡塞尔
Castle,
你妈妈有问题
something's wrong with your mother.
你才发现吗
You're just realizing this now?
-不是  听啊  -他死了吗
- No, no. shh. listen. - Is he dead?
他死了吗
Is he dead?!
她在做48小时首句预热
She's doing 48-hour first line.
对了  你住在这里期间
Oh, that's right. You haven't lived here
还没经历过妈妈为首演做准备呢
while mother is preparing to open in a play.
信不信由你  但这是她
This, believe it or not, is her little ritual
进入角色的小仪式
for getting into character.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
好吧  那么这是正常的了
Okay, so, this is normal?
她是个演员  怎么算正常啊
She's an actor. What's normal?
我称之为"48小时首句预热"
I call it "48-hour first line"
因为首演前两天内
Because for the two days prior to opening night,
她就只肯
she will say nothing
说她角色在剧中的第一句
but her character's first line of the play.
好吧  还挺特别的
Okay, that's unique.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
但是她的剧不是下月才首演吗
But doesn't her play open next month?
是啊
That's right.
两天之后的是预演
It's previews that are two days away.
这是挺奇怪的
Oh, no, that is odd.
卡塞尔  发生了凶案
Oh, Castle, there's been a homicide.
-他死了吗  -很不幸  是的  玛莎
- Is he dead? - Yes, unfortunately, Martha...
嗯  当我没说
Right. Never mind.
说老实话  当初许下婚誓说要"同甘共苦"时
Be honest. When you vowed "for better or for worse,"
根本没想到会摊上这种事吧
you really had no idea what you were getting into, did you?
-他死了吗  -回见了  妈妈
- Is he dead? Is he dead? - See you, mother.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
他...
Is...
我们可以去住酒店
We can stay at a hotel.
这样你就不用反复听她
That way, you don't have to listen to her say that line
-说那句台词了  -没事啦
- over and over again. - No, it's okay.
我们不会有事的  就是你妈妈有点...
I mean, we're gonna manage. It's just, your mom's kind of...
烦人  是啊  我知道
Annoying? Yeah, I know.
相信我  这算好的了
Trust me, we're getting off easy.
有次她的首句是
One time her opening line was,
"来啊  宝贝  我会让你爽到的"
"Come on, baby. I'll make it worth your while."
-我明白你意思了  -是啊
- Ooh, I see what you mean. - Yeah.
史上最尴尬的家长会
Most awkward parent-teacher conference ever.
-蕾妮  -早啊  二位
- Hey, Lanie. - Good morning, you two.
-这是  -希德·罗斯
- This is... - Sid Ross!
《今晚周六夜》的编剧
The creator of "Saturday Night Tonight."
是啊  还制作了好多的电影
Yeah, not to mention all the movies he produced.
-他是行业巨头啊  -怎么回事
- The man's a mogul. - So, what happened?
他被用自己的领带勒死了
He was strangled with his own tie
然后被从7楼的SNT演播室
and then thrown down that elevator shaft
丢下了电梯井
from the "S.N.T." studios on the seventh floor.
尸体在电梯顶上躺了几小时
His body was on the roof of that elevator for hours
顶板终于支持不住  他才落了下来
before the panel gave way and Sid popped out.
像地狱来的玩偶盒
Like some jack-in-the-box from hell.
-死亡时间  -从尸斑来看
- Time of death? - Based on lividity,
晚上11点到凌晨2点间
between 11:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m.
看来希德在开夜车呢
Looks like Sid was burning the midnight oil.
我们问问保安  看他们是否知道
Let's check with security, see if they know
当时还有没有其他人在楼内
if anyone else was in the building with him.
考虑到我们在哪
Considering where we are,
或许是希德手下的员工杀了他
maybe one of Sid's employees killed him.
莱恩和埃斯波西托正带他妻子去警局
Yeah, well, Ryan and Esposito are bringing his wife in now.
或许她知道会是谁干的
Maybe she knows who would have done this to him.
大家都怕希德
Everyone was scared of Sid,
但他们不像我那么了解他
but they didn't know him like I did.
他们都把他当做冷漠的独裁者
They thought he was just a cold, tyrannical dictator.
听起来他有树敌
Sounds like he had enemies.
35年来他成就不少人  也毁了不少人
After 35 years of making and breaking careers, you...
难免会惹到一些人
You're bound to piss off a few people.
《今晚周六夜》的人呢
Anyone at "Saturday Night Tonight" studio?
他跟哪个雇员有矛盾吗
Yeah, was he having trouble with any of his employees there?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能吧
Maybe. Uh...
希德昨晚打给我  很奇怪
Eh, Sid called me last night. It was odd.
他说他要晚归
Uh, he said he was going to be working late.
-这不寻常吗  -不
- And that's unusual? - No.
他是个工作狂
He was a workaholic.
怪在他的语气  他很紧张
The odd part was his tone. It was anxious.
他说有人针对他
He said someone was out to get him,
他得处理一下
and he needed to handle it.
知道可能是谁吗
Any idea who that someone might be?
我以为又是他生意上的事
Well, I just assumed it was one of his big business deals.
还有别人可能知道希德在做什么吗
Is there anyone else who might know what Sid was involved in?
是的  他制作公司的老板  基恩·沃格尔
Yes. The head of his production company, Gene Vogel.
沃格尔先生就在这边
Mr. Vogel is right over here.
查德  是叫查德吧
Chad... it's Chad, right?
这是整35季以来的卡司照片吗
Are these cast photos from all 35 seasons of the show?
是的  每位上过SNT的演员
Yep. Every performer who has ever been on "S.N.T."
我好喜欢他的  他扮演太空狗毛毛
Oh, I liked him. He played fluffy the space puppy.
我最喜欢了
That was my favorite.
本国大部分的喜剧
You know, a majority of this nation's comedy
都来自这些天才的头脑
was born in the minds of these geniuses.
除了这一季  他们好烂
Except for this season. Those guys sucked.
-是啊  他们不怎么样  -这家伙
- Yeah, they were terrible. - Oh, this guy!
内德什么来着  他扮演手指医生
Uh, Ned what's-his-name? He played, uh, doctor finger.
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
我必须检查你一下
It's necessary I must probe you.
你怎么可能不喜欢手指医生
How can you not like doctor finger?
因为  卡塞尔  我不是13岁的男生
Because, Castle, I wasn't a 13-year-old boy.
检查...
Probe...
沃格尔先生在那边
That's Mr. Vogel.
他是罗斯先生制作公司的总裁
He's the president of Mr. Ross' production company.
大家聚过来
Gather 'round, please.
谢谢大家
Thank you, everybody.
希德的死虽然很悲剧
As tragic as Sid's death is,
电视台希望我们继续
the network has asked us to go on
明晚的节目  向他致敬
with tomorrow night's show... as a tribute.
要说几句吗
Would you care to say a few words?
看啊  是丹...
Check it out. That's Dan--
-丹尼·瓦伦汀  -丹尼·瓦伦汀
- Danny Valentine! - Danny Valentine!
他是本周嘉宾主持
He's our guest host this week.
我还记得试播集时  希德要我主持
I remember when Sid asked me to host the pilot
这个疯狂的节目
of this...crazy show.
大家都说拒绝他  这节目不会火的
Everybody said, "Turn him down. Show's a dud."
然而35年后  还是势头不减
Well, 35 years later, it's still going strong.
我们通过尊重他的作品向希德致敬
We honor Sid by honoring his creation.
所以  我们开始演出吧
So...let's put on a show.
沃格尔先生  不好意思  我是
Mr. Vogel, excuse me. I'm --
凯特·贝克特探长
Detective Kate Beckett.
你就是理查德·卡塞尔
And you're Richard Castle.
你好我是利兹·贝尔  《今晚周六夜》的总编剧
Hi, I'm Liz Bell. I'm the head writer for "S.N.T."
我非常崇拜你
And I absolutely adore you.
还有你  特别是你
And you. Especially you.
-我吗  真的吗  -当然啦
- Me? Really? Uh -- oh, of course.
我一直关注你的事业  我曾想当个警察
I followed your career. I wanted to be a cop,
但最后却成了编剧
but ended up a writer.
是啊  很悲哀对吧
I know. It's pathetic.
-你说什么  -我看了
- Excuse me? - So I've seen footage
你办案时候的录像  我得问你
of your crime scenes, and I have to ask --
你是怎么做到一边办案一边保持发型的
how do you fight crime and keep your hair like that?
还穿着高跟鞋
And do it in high heels!
探长
Detective,
我想你是为希德之死而来
I assume you're here about Sid's death.
-有什么能帮上忙  -我们与保安进行了核实
- How can I help? - Well, uh, we checked with security,
我得知大多数的员工
and I understand that most employees enter and exit
都是通过前门进出  但是显然
through the front door, but apparently there's also
-还有一个私人贵宾入口吗  -是的
- a private V.I.P entrance? - That's right.
希德是为了演员们设置了那个入口
Sid had it installed for the actors
让他们进出时能更为隐蔽
so they could come and go with more privacy.
那个私人入口处有监控摄像头吗
Are there any security cameras on that private entrance?
他们是演员
They're actors,
他们会用那个入口做些别的事情  比如
so they also use it to do other things, like --
希德决定不用监控
Sid opted not to have surveillance.
所以没有办法知道有谁
So there's no way of telling who came in or out
-从那个入口进出吗  -恐怕没有
- of the private entrance? - I'm afraid not.
昨晚有人在这里工作吗
Was anyone working here last night
在十点到凌晨两点之间
between 11:00 p.m. And 2:00 a.m.?
是的  所有的编剧和演员
Yes. All the writers and actors.
星期四是剧本改写之夜
Thursday is rewrite night.
大多数的人都在这待到第二天早上
So most of them were here until sunup.
在这些人中  有人和希德不和吗
Of those people, did anyone have a problem with Sid?
是谁
Who?
对不起先生  我们还没开始营业
Sorry, sir, we're not quite open yet.
我把所有排练都录下来了
Uh, I record all of our rehearsals.
这是昨晚的事
This took place yesterday evening.
伙计  你怎么穿着盔甲
Dude, why are you wearing armor?
因为这个短剧太糟糕了  我要拯救它
Because the sketch sucks, and I'm trying to save it!
麦基·弗兰克斯很搞笑
Mickey Franks is hilarious.
是啊  继续看
Yes, well, just watch.
麦基  你不能这么做
Mickey, you can't do this!
希德已经批准了这个短剧
Sid already approved the sketch.
你知道吗  去他的希德
You know, screw Sid.
去他的希德
Screw Sid!
你想知道我觉得希德是什么样的吗
You want to know what I think of Sid?
我觉得希德就是这样
That's what I think of Sid!
希德去死  他是个死人
Sid's dead, that's what he is!
对我来说他已经死了
He's dead to me!
我会杀了他  他得去死
I'll kill him! He's dead!
他死了  死了  死了  死了
He's dead! He's dead! He's dead! He's dead! He's...
这季以来  麦基越来越不稳定
Over this season, Mickey's become more and more unstable.
情绪不稳定  突然发狂  自言自语
Mood swings, outbursts, talks to himself --
还和不在场的人说话
and to people who aren't there.
但那是他第一次这样
But that was the first time he ever went this far.
他为什么要对希德这么生气呢
Well, did he have a reason to be angry with Sid?
除了这个差劲的短剧外
Aside from the lame sketch?
事实上有  我昨天早上和希德谈过
Actually, yes. I talked to Sid yesterday morning.
他说他打算炒掉麦基
He said he was planning to fire Mickey.
他怎么想要解雇他的明星呢
How can he fire his star?
他很不稳定  难以预测
Ah...he's volatile, unpredictable.
越来越像个累赘
He's become more and more of a liability.
沃格尔先生  昨晚希德和麦基摊牌了吗
Mr. Vogel, did Sid break the news to Mickey last night?
我不知道  有可能
I don't know, but he might have.
麦基没有参加为希德举办的聚会
Well, Mickey wasn't at the gathering for Sid.
-他在大楼内吗  -如果他在的话
- Is he in the building? - If he is,
他肯定会在服装道具室里面
he'll be in the wardrobe and props room.
他经常在那想新的角色
He hangs out there to develop new characters.
有人在吗
Hello? Anybody there?
我真希望麦基不是凶手
I'm really hoping Mickey's not the one behind this.
这人在节目里实在是太搞笑了
I mean, the man is just so damn funny on the show,
即使在很烂的几集里
even the crappy episodes.
这家伙太搞笑了
Guy's hysterical.
而且很可能精神崩溃
And quite possibly suffering a psychotic break.
对啊  天才和疯子只有一线之差
Yes. The fine line between genius and madness.
麦基·弗兰克斯  是你吗
Mickey Franks, is that you?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你肯定是把我当做另一套盔甲了
You must have mistaken me for another suit of armor.
恕我失陪
Now if you'll excuse me.
纽约警局  我们得谈谈
N.Y.P.D. We need to talk.
你别想活捉我  警察
You'll never take me alive, copper!
天哪  我的胰腺啊
Oh! My pancreas!
你瞧啊  即使被捕他还是很搞笑
You see what I'm saying? Even arrested, he's hilarious!
弗兰克斯先生
Mr. Franks.
你就是个喜剧天才  我是你的超级粉丝
You're a comedic genius. I'm a huge fan.
弗兰克斯先生
Mr. Franks.
请把你的所有问题都交给我的律师
Please direct all your questions to my personal attorney.
麦基
Mickey,
别再说话了
don't say another word.
我是弗兰克斯先生的首席律师
I'm lead counsel for Mr. Franks.
弗兰克斯先生
Uh, Mr. Franks,
你昨晚恐吓了希德·罗斯
you made some threats against Sid Ross last night.
你说得对  别回答
You're damn right I -- don't answer that!
探长  请让我来回答你的问题
Detective, address your questions to me, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在哪里
Uh, where were --
昨晚十一点到凌晨两点
Where...was your client
你的委托人在哪里
between 11:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m. last night?
他在做他自己的事
He was minding his own damn business!
我的委托人是一位正直的公民
My client is an upstanding citizen
并且是社会的砥柱中流
and a pillar of the community.
更别说他还是个幽默的混小子
Not to mention, he's also one funny mother-fudgesicle.
注意你的措辞
Hey, watch your language.
麦基  发生了什么
What happened, Mickey?
是希德跟你说你被解雇了
Did Sid tell you you were fired,
你就暴发把他给杀了
so you snapped and killed him?
等等  什么
Hold on, what?
希德死了吗
Sid -- Sid's dead?
嘿  我  我
Whoa, hey, oh -- oh, whoa, I --
我没有杀他
I didn't kill him.
你不再向你的律师求助了
I noticed you're no long seeking counsel from your attorney.
没有  那就是表演
Yeah, no, that's -- that's just an act.
我没疯
I mean...I'm not crazy.
我只是花了一年的时间让大家觉得我疯了
Just spent a year of my life convincing people that I was.
这件事上你做得非常好
Yeah, and you've done a pretty good job of it.
我是个演员  好吗
I'm an actor, okay?
我是个签了很长合约的演员
I am an actor that's tied to a long-term contract
而且这份合约还让我入不敷出
that's, uh...not exactly covering his expenses.
你是说你想被解雇掉
Are you saying you were trying to get fired?
我是说  希德掌控了我的演艺生涯
I mean, Sid controls my career.
因为他  我错失了很多电影主演的机会
Because of him, I'm missing out on major movie roles.
所以我才袭击了你们
That's why I attacked you guys.
我想如果你们能认定我是精神病患者
I figured maybe if you 5150 me on a bellevue psych hold,
他就终于会想摆脱我
he would finally cut me loose.
好吧  不管疯不疯
Okay, look, crazy or not,
你始终撂狠话威胁了希德
You still made some pretty serious threats against Sid,
而几小时后他就死了
and hours later he ended up dead.
好吧  你问我当时在哪是吧
Okay -- you're asking my whereabouts, right? Mm.
我整晚都在楼上的屋顶酒吧喝酒
Okay, I was upstairs at the rooftop bar getting wasted all night.
凌晨三点左右我跌跌撞撞地去了服装道具室
And then I stumbled down to the wardrobe and props room
然后就不省人事了
at about 3:00 A.M. and passed out.
你们进来的时候我才刚醒
I had just woken up when you guys came in.
而且  我都不知道希德死了
Plus, I had no idea Sid was even dead,
-我怎么可能跟这事有关呢  -好吧
- so how could I have had anything to do with it? - Okay.
不过  我可能知道是谁干的
Look, I might know who did!
好啊
Okay.
我们听着呢
We're listening.
昨晚大约九点左右
Look, at around 9:00 P.M. Last night,
我去了希德的办公室
I...did go to Sid's office
想求他解除我的合同
to beg to be let out of my contract.
可我根本没进去  因为我听到他在打电话
But I never went in because I heard him on the phone.
他在冲某人大吼
He was yelling at someone.
-他在吼谁  -不知道
- Who was he yelling at? - I don't know.
但好像跟什么交易有关
But it had something to do with a deal
是要半夜进行的
that was going down around midnight.
半夜  他说了是什么交易吗
Midnight? Did he say what the deal was?
没有  但希德在电话里告诉那人
No. But Sid told that person on the phone
他们最好按什么约定来  否则后果自负
they better stick to the agreement, or else.
我能打给我真正的律师了吗
Can I call my real attorney?
酒保证实了麦基的不在场证明
The bartender confirmed Mickey's alibi.
他不是凶手
He's not our killer.
那可以假设麦基说的是实话了
Well, then we can assume Mickey was telling the truth
他确实听到了希德的那通电话
about the phone call he overheard Sid making.
对  但希德会在大半夜做什么交易呢
Yeah, but what kind of deal would Sid be making at midnight?
不管是什么  这事跟他死亡的时间线吻合
Whatever it was, it went down in the middle of his time of death window.
所以可能跟他的死有关
So this deal could be connected to his death.
我们得查清跟希德通电话的人是谁
We need to figure out who Sid was talking on the phone with.
你倒是站着说话不腰痛
Well, that's easier said than done.
我刚查了希德的通话记录
I just got Sid's phone dump.
昨晚九点有一通电话
A 9:00 P.M. Phone call
来自一部反追踪的一次性手机
came from an untraceable burner phone.
这样吧  不如我们先找找希德的生意伙伴
You know what? Why don't we get ahold of Sid's associates,
看看他们是否有人知道是什么交易
see if any of them know what this deal was.
我知道该从谁开始
I know who exactly who to start with.
就在那通神秘电话后
Right after that mystery call,
希德给丹尼·瓦伦汀打了电话
Sid phoned none other than Danny Valentine.
要是有人知道那交易是什么  一定是瓦伦汀
If anyone knows about that deal, it's Valentine.
探长  我完全不知道你在说什么
Detective, I have no idea what you're talking about.
伙计  我是警察  而且是模特
Look, buddy, I'm a cop and a model,
我能看出来有人在说谎
So I know when someone's lying to me.
或是衣服穿得不合适
and when their outfit is clashing.
退后  这可能很危险
Now stand back! This could be dangerous!
别担心  我写罪案小说的经验
Don't worry. My experience writing crime novels
已经帮我做好了应对危险的准备
has prepared me for danger.
而且  我还有防弹衣呢
Plus, I have my vest.
小心点  坏蛋们  我们来了
Look out, bad guys, here we come!
糟糕  模特警察要倒了
Uhh! Oh, model cop down!
我鞋跟断了
I broke a heel!
完成  很好  伙计们
And scene! Great job, guys.
真不知道我们该觉得荣幸还是生气
Okay, well, I don't know whether we should be flattered or offended.
谁在乎啊  丹尼·瓦伦汀在演我
Who cares? Danny Valentine's playing me!
你们觉得怎么样
Well, what do you think?
短剧吗  挺...可爱
Um, about the sketch? It's...uh, cute.
丹尼·瓦伦汀演的是我
Danny Valentine's playing me.
是啊
Yeah.
说到瓦伦汀先生
Speaking of Mr. Valentine,
我们得跟他谈谈
We need to talk to him.
丹尼
Oh. Uh, Danny?
真警察来了
Aha! The real police.
是来指导我们的吗
Here to give us some pointers?
瓦伦汀先生  我是理查德·卡塞尔
Mr. Valentine, Richard Castle.
我是你的大粉...
I'm a big fan of --
嗯  你呢  探长
Yeah. What about you, detective?
你也是我的粉丝吗
Are you a fan?
瓦伦汀先生  我们得谈谈
Yeah... Uh, Mr. Valentine, we need to...talk.
当然  去我的更衣室吧
Sure. Let's go to my dressing room.
你肯定看过我很多作品吧
Surely you've seen some of my work --
《星际舰队》《大众医疗》
"Star fleet"? "Family practice"?
还有我那些租车的广告
My, uh, my car rental commercials?
我在大学的时候确实看过
Uh, yeah, well, I-I did catch my fair share
《通缉犯》的重播
of "Hot suspect" reruns in college.
我就知道  警察肯定爱看警匪剧
I knew it! The cop watched the cop show.
承认吧  我激发了你当警察的志向  对不对
Come on, I inspired you to become a detective, didn't I? Huh?
可能有点吧
Maybe a little bit.
我们在调查一起谋杀案  对吧
We're investigating a murder, right?
对对  我们查了希德的电话记录
Right. Yeah. Uh, so... we checked Sid's phone records,
看来他昨晚9:03给你打过电话
and apparently he called you at 9:03 last night.
能告诉我们为什么吗
Can you tell us why?
我本来要去跟希德和他前妻伊芙琳小酌几杯的
Yeah, I was supposed to have drinks with sid and his ex, Evelyn.
可临到头他却打电话来取消了
But Sid called last minute to cancel.
你和希德要跟他前妻一起小聚
You and Sid were going out with his ex-wife?
-这有点奇怪吧  -对我们来说不会
- Isn't that a little odd? - Not for us.
希德和伊芙琳二十年前就分开了
Sid and Evelyn split 20 years ago,
但我们仍是很要好的朋友
but we were all still close friends.
他有说为什么要取消吗
Did he say why he was canceling?
恐怕没有
Afraid not.
他有提过半夜的什么交易吗
Anything about a deal at midnight?
没有  但他要去个什么地方
No, but he was going somewhere,
因为他在讲电话时
Because while we were on the phone,
我亲眼看到他从大楼的私人出口离开了
I literally bumped into him leaving the building from the private entrance.
等等  希德遇害当晚
Wait, Sid was leaving the building
离开了大楼
the night of his murder?
瓦伦汀先生  他有提过要跟谁见面吗
Uh, Mr. Valentine, did he mention meeting with someone?
拜托  叫我丹尼就好
Please. Call me Danny.
没有  希德没说他要去哪
And, no, Sid didn't say where he was going.
但我确实看到一些奇怪的事
But I did see something strange.
他进了街角的地铁站
He went into the subway on the corner.
那怎么奇怪了  丹尼
And why was that strange, Danny?
他有24小时的私人司机
Well, he had an around-the-clock driver,
为什么要去搭乘公共交通工具呢
So why would he take mass transit?
除非是个秘密约会
Unless it was a secret rendezvous?
不管希德去了哪
Well, wherever Sid went,
他显然不想让任何人知道
He obviously didn't want anyone to know about it.
拜托  卡塞尔
Oh, come on, Castle.
是他要跟我调情  我也没办法啊
He was flirting with me. I can't control that.
可你也回调他了
But you were flirting right back.
是  不然我该怎么做
Yeah, but what was I supposed to do?
他可是丹尼·瓦伦汀啊
He's Danny frickin' Valentine.
埃斯波
Espo, hey.
查到希德搭地铁去哪了吗
You find out where Sid went on that subway ride?
还没  但我跟他公司的基恩·沃格尔聊了
Not yet, but I spoke to Gene Vogel from Sid's company.
他所知的唯一一笔交易
The only deal that he knew about was one
是尚未经官方公布的
that hasn't been officially announced yet.
希德要把他公司49%的股份
Apparently Sid was gonna sell
卖给一家股权公司
49% of his company to an equity firm.
那会是希德提到的交易吗
Could that be the deal sid was talking about?
不太像  出售条款应该几周前就拟定了
Doesn't look like it. The terms of the sale would have been settled weeks ago.
没有什么可谈的了
There was nothing left to negotiate.
各位  你们过来看看吧
Hey, guys, you're gonna wanna see this.
虽然希德用现金买的地铁卡
So, Sid paid for his metro card in cash,
不过我还是通过监控录像
but I was able to use security cams to track him
在大军团广场地铁站找到了他
all the way to Grand Army Plaza subway station.
他晚上十一点半在那下的车
He got off there at 11:30 P.M.
布鲁克林  他去布鲁克林干什么
In Brooklyn. What was he doing in Brooklyn?
我也有同样的问题
You know, I wondered the same thing,
所以我跟八十七分局核实了一下
so I checked with the 87th Precinct.
他们接到了一通从那个地方打来的报警电话
Apparently they responded to a 9-1-1 call in that area.
-什么事  -自己看吧
- About what? - Well, check it out.
警用交通录像
Officers used traffic cam footage,
拍到了事件结束时的画面
And they caught the tail end of it.
这里距离希德下地铁的地方大约有一个街区
This is about a block away from where Sid got off the subway.
看好了那个小巷子
Now keep your eye on that alley right there.
-是打枪吗  -跟报警电话描述的吻合
- Were those gunshots? - Fits with the 9-1-1 call.
报警者说有人开枪了
There was a report of shots fired.
看看接下来发生的
Now watch what happens next.
那是希德
That's Sid.
各位  看一下时间戳
You guys, look at the timestamp.
刚过午夜十二点
It's from just after midnight.
这一定就是他所说的交易
This must be the deal he was talking about.
从他这个六十多岁人的移动速度来判断
And judging by the speed his 60-year-old legs are moving,
我觉得他一定是处于危险之中
I would say he's in danger.
那人是谁
Who's that?
不知道  不过他手里有枪
I don't know, but he's got a gun
而且还戴着面具
and he's wearing a mask.
不久之后  希德就从电梯井上栽下来了
And hours later, Sid gets thrown down an elevator shaft.
希德摊上什么事了
What the hell was Sid mixed up in?
各位  你们难道
You guys, is it just me,
不觉得这说不通吗
or does none of this make sense?
希德的财产有好几百万
I mean, Sid was a multimillionaire.
他这样的人绝不会在黑巷子里做见不得人的交易
Guys like that don't make shady deals in the middle of dark alleys.
就算真要做  也会找别人替他做
Or if you do, you have someone else do it for you.
是的  看看这个嫌犯
Yeah, and take a look at our suspect there.
是交易出了岔子  还是没杀死
I mean, what is this, a deal gone wrong or a failed hit?
是不是说  这个戴面具的人
So what are we saying here, that the masked man
跟踪希德回到了SNT大楼
followed Sid back to the "S.N.T." building
然后杀了他
and killed him?
既然有个没装监控的私人入口
Well, with a private entrance with no surveillance cameras,
这也是有可能的  对吧
it's possible, right?
可是既然有人要杀他
But after an apparent attempt on his life,
希德为什么还要回办公室呢
why would Sid just go back to the office?
而且如果希德真的有危险  他为什么不找保安呢
And if Sid really was in danger, why didn't he call security?
我们或许能在那个小巷子里找到答案
Well, we may find some answers in that alley.
我们去看看吧
Let's go check it out.
好的  卡塞尔和我再看一下交通录像
Okay, Castle and I are gonna scrub traffic cams.
或许能从中找出枪手
Maybe we'll find the shooter there.
找到什么了吗
Anything yet?
没有
No.
没有血迹  没有弹壳  什么都没有
No blood, no shell casings, no nothing.
这有没有让你想起《夜晚周六夜》中的
Hey, doesn't this remind you of that sketch
麦基·弗兰克斯演夏洛克·福尔摩斯
from "Saturday Night Tonight" where, Mickey Franks
古怪的表弟的那个短剧
plays Sherlock Holmes' wacky cousin?
没有  我不看那个无聊的节目
No, I don't watch that stupid show, bro.
你不看
You don't?
不看
No.
当然不看了  那些短剧从来没有结局
Hell, no. The sketches never have any endings.
简直是浪费时间
It's a big waste of time,
搜查这个巷子也是浪费时间
Just like searching this alley is.
哈维  你得想个办法
You know, Javi, I think that you need
让自己阳光一些
to find a way to be more positive.
不  我不需要
No, I don't.
你也别总是说"不"了
And you need to stop saying "No" all the time.
其实  你为什么不能说"好的  而且..."
Instead, why don't you try saying "Yes, and..."?
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
这是我上大学时在即兴表演课上学的
Oh, I learned it in a "S.N.T." sponsored
那课程是SNT发起的
improvisation class I took in college.
你看  只需要把"不"换成"好的  而且"
See, by simply substituting "No" With "Yes, and..."
搭档们就不能打断彼此的进展
partners can't deny one another's progress
必须继续演下去  直至完成目标
moving forward in a scene and accomplishing goals.
那个人或许昨天晚上也在这
Yo. That guy might have been here last night.
是的  而且他可能还看到了
Yes, and he might have seen the exchange
希德和枪手之间的交易
between Sid and the gunman.
说了"好的[是]  而且"就会有收获吧
See what you can accomplish by saying "Yes, and..."?
是的  而且你得闭嘴了
Yes, and you need to shut the hell up.
玛莎  你还好吗
Martha, you okay?
是的  是的  只是有点累了  没事的
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Just a... little tired, that's all.
走吧
Shall we?
你妈妈好像有点问题
Something's wrong with your mom.
我们不是已经谈过这事了吗
I thought we already covered that.
不是  不是  她不再重复台词了
No, no, no. She's not repeating the lines.
是有别的问题了
Something else is going on.
她不重复了不是更好吗
Can't we just be happy that she stopped?
卡塞尔  我得去警局了
Castle, I have to go to the precinct.
你能不能跟她谈谈  然后去警局找我
Will you just talk to her and meet me over there?
-可以  -好的  再见
- Yeah. - OK. Bye.
-再见  玛莎  -再见  亲爱的
- Bye, Martha. - Bye, honey.
那个
So...
今晚试映
previews tonight.
很激动吧
Pretty exciting?
"他死了吗"
Come on. "Is he dead?"
问得不对
Wrong question.
应该问我死了吗
Am I dead?
我不知道我在想什么
You know, I don't know what I'm thinking.
一周演八次
Eight performances a week,
百老汇的重要剧目
major play on Broadway.
你之前也在百老汇演过
You've been on Broadway before.
这个嘛
Well...
克林顿下台后就没再演过了
not since the Clinton administration.
现在是网络时代了
And now it's all viral.
博客  推特
Bloggers, tweeters.
很多人会来看试映
You know, people actually come to the previews,
然后用手机拍下来
record the show on their phone,
传到网上  评论一番
put it online, and make comments.
可你觉得你的表演还没准备好吗
And you don't feel your performance is ready?
我只是
Well, I just -- I --
我还在琢磨我的戏
I'm still honing my performance.
这就是  这才叫试映嘛
That's what a -- that's what previews are for,
我只是
And I just...
我只是不想丢脸
I just don't want to be humiliated.
我拿到这个角色时  我就想
When I got this part, I thought, well, hey,
我有机会了
there's a chance, you know?
这可能是我演艺生涯的第二幕
This could be my second act.
-的确是  -不  不是的
- It is. - No, it isn't.
不是的  我不会有第二幕了
It isn't. I'm not gonna have a second act.
我
I...
我觉得我应该退出
I think what I need to do is just drop out,
-让我的替角登场  她很...  -绝对不行
- let my understudy take over. She's very... - Oh, absolutely not.
你不能退出  知道为什么吗
You will not, and do you know why?
因为你是个斗士  你怎么教育我的
Because you're a fighter. What have you always told me?
这辈子没人会给你什么
No one will give you anything in this life.
你要自己争取
You must earn it.
看看你  将近二十年了
And look at you. Almost 20 years later,
又要重回百老汇
and you're back on Broadway?
这是你争来的
You have earned this.
我争来的  对吧
I have, haven't I?
是的
You have.
别让个拿手机的笨蛋
Please don't let some idiot with a cell phone
把那个从你手中夺去
take that away from you.
要我今晚去看你的演出吗
Do you want me to come to tonight's show,
精神上支持你
just for moral support?
我还是希望你来看首演  孩子
I want you to come to the opening, kiddo,
就像你以前一样
just like you always do.
好的
All right.
不过如果要我等的话  至少先让我
But if I have to wait, at least let me hear
再听一次你美妙的开场白吧
that sweet first line one more time.
行
Okay, um...
他死了吗
Is he dead?
带点感情
But with feeling!
他死了吗
Is he dead?
给后面的观众再来一遍
One more for the cheap seats!
他死了吗
Is he dead?!
他死翘翘了
He's so dead!
鞠躬...
And bow...
流浪汉那有什么消息没
Hey. So what'd you guys get from the homeless man?
他没有目击希德和蒙面枪手之间的"对话"
He didn't witness the exchange between Sid and our masked gunman.
但他的确听到了枪声
However, he did hear the gunshots
几分钟后看到一辆黑色探险者驶离现场
and a few minutes later he saw a black Explorer speeding away.
-他看到车牌了吗  -是的  后四位
- Did he get a plate? - Yeah, the last four numbers,
帮我们找到了一辆匹配的SUV
which got us a match to an SUV.
是这家伙租的...
rented by this guy --
科特·范·赞特
Kurt Van Zant.
因贩毒在福尔松监狱服了35年的刑
Just did a 35-year stretch in Folsom for drug trafficking,
但他刚被释放
but he was just released.
希德和这前科犯有什么关联吗
Is there a connection between Sid and this ex-con?
有的  范·赞特还在监狱里时
Oh, yeah. Uh, while he was in prison,
他向法院提起诉讼  声称是他为
Van Zant filed a lawsuit claiming that he financed
《今晚周六夜》首播集融资
the pilot for "Saturday Night Tonight"
而希德却让他一分好处没有捞到
and that Sid screwed him out of all the profits.
等等  你是说
Wait a minute. You're telling me
毒枭给这个喜剧节目提供了资金支持
that a drug kingpin bankrolled that comedy show?
没错
Yeah, I know.
听上去就像是他们的某个喜剧段子
It sounds like one of their comedy sketches, right?
就是说这个给全国观众带去欢声笑语的节目
So a show that brought joy, laughter, and "Judge Booty"
可能是由贩毒的钱起家的
to people everywhere may have been built on drug money.
是的  可诉讼被否
Yeah, but the lawsuit was thrown out,
希德数钞票时  范·赞特却在坐穿牢底
so while Sid was getting rich, Van Zant was rotting in prison.
也许范·赞特就是希德跟他妻子说的
You know, maybe Van Zant was who Sid was talking about
那个要找他麻烦的人
when he told his wife someone was after him.
有道理
Makes sense, right?
也许范·赞特觉得希德欠他
If Van Zant felt that Sid owed him a share
节目的利润  所以就来找他要了
of the profits from the show, maybe he came to collect.
结果希德并没有乖乖给钱
And when Sid didn't want to go along,
范·赞特就选择了复仇
Van Zant opted for revenge instead.
范·赞特现在在哪里
Where is Van Zant now?
他在皇后区的一家旅店登记入住了
He's registered at a hotel up in Queens.
我把范·赞特的照片给SNT的保安看了
Yo. I sent Van Zant's photo to security at "S.N.T.",
问有没有人昨晚看到过他
asked if anybody saw him last night.
没人看到  但30分钟之前
No one did. However, 30 minutes ago,
范·赞特进入了大楼
Van Zant entered the building
是剧组里的某人给了他通行证
on a day pass called in from someone at the show.
科特·范·赞特  不是说真的吧
Kurt Van Zant? You got to be kidding me.
你认识他吗
Yeah. Do you know him?
不  不过希德跟我讲过他很多事
No, but Sid told me all about him.
他可是个危险人物
He's dangerous.
你是说他现在在演播室里
You're telling me he's here in the studio?
你知道是谁给他弄的通行证吗
Do you know who called in his pass?
不  不过我能查到
No, but I can find out.
跟我来
Follow me.
有什么事情吗
Um, um, can I help you?
不  没事
Oh, no, it's fine.
只是你的步态非常奇特
You just have a very bizarre gait.
抱...抱歉  什么
I'm -- I'm sorry, what?
抱歉  什么
I'm sorry, what?
搞定
Nailed it.
卡塞尔  告诉我我不是那样子的
Castle, please tell me I don't move like that.
我是那样的吗
I mean...do I?
这是陷阱问题吗
Is this a trick question?
哪个答案不会让我今晚睡在沙发上
What answer is not gonna have me sleeping on the couch tonight?
查德  找出是谁给科特·范·赞特发的通行证
Chad, find out who called in a day pass for a Kurt Van Zant.
就站在你眼前  先生
You're looking at him, sir.
什么  是你发的通行证  为什么
Wait a minute. You called in the pass? Why?
是瓦伦汀先生让我发的
I was told to by Mr. Valentine.
-丹尼·瓦伦汀  -丹尼·瓦伦汀
- Danny Valentine? - Danny Valentine!
我就知道
Oh, I knew it.
那个混蛋  毫无才华的花花公子...
That smug, no-talent playboy --
他就是这一切的幕后黑手
He's up to his neck in this!
救命  救命
Hey, hey! Hey! Help! Help!
救命  他要杀我
Help! He's gonna kill me!
-不  救命  -纽约警局
- Wait, no! Help! - N.Y.P.D.!
救命
Help! Aah!
放开他[让他掉下去]
Let him go!
什么  不
What?! No!
把他拉进来  范·赞特  马上
Pull him in, Van Zant, now!
女士  别激动
Hey, lady, relax!
让我看到你的双手
Come on, let me see your hands.
多谢
Thanks.
这家伙是个疯子
Guy's a psychopath.
那你为什么要给他通行证
Then why did you give him a pass to get on?
他在我酒店留了张字条
He left a note at my hotel.
说是有关于希德被害的信息
He said he had information about Sid's murder.
你是说你并不认识这个人吗
Are you saying you don't know this man?
我今天之前都没见过他
I never him before today.
这整件事是个天大的误会
Listen, this whole thing is a big misunderstanding.
肯定是  走
I'm sure it is. Come on.
关于希德被害  他到底知道些什么
So what information did he have about Sid's murder?
什么都没有  他就是来要钱的
Nothing. I mean, this was a shakedown.
他声称希德欠他《今晚周六夜》的钱
He claimed Sid owed him money for "Saturday Night Tonight",
鉴于希德没给他钱  他就想让我
but since Sid didn't pay, he wanted me
把我的那份转让给他
to sign over my shares of the show.
-你也有节目的股份  -5%
- You own a piece of the show? - Mm, 5%.
希德需要一个名人上首播集
Sid needed a -- a celebrity get for the pilot,
所以他就分了我一部分
so he gave me a piece of the back end.
这是我一生最棒的交易
It was the deal of my life.
范·赞特想要他的那一份  但希德死了
So Van Zant wanted his cut, but with Sid dead,
他唯一的选择是来找你要
his only option was to come after yours.
我拒绝了
I refused.
我说"这就是演艺圈  伙计"
I-I said, "Hey, that's show business, baby",
他听后就开始把我往窗户外面推
but that's when he started shoving me out the window.
在福尔松蹲了35年
35 years in Folsom.
范·赞特先生  怨恨这么久还没消
That's a long time to hold a grudge, Mr. Van Zant.
女士  我没有杀希德
Lady, I didn't kill Sid.
可你却被看到逃离发生枪击的小巷
And yet you were seen fleeing the alley where those shots were fired.
不难想象  你会跟踪希德
It's not hard to imagine that you would follow Sid
然后把他结果掉
and finish off the job.
听着  你全都弄错了
Look. You got this all wrong!
假释出来之后  我直接去找了希德
When I got paroled, I went straight to Sid.
我们都谈妥了  他也道歉了
We had it out, and he apologized.
结果他现在却死了
Except now he's dead.
我为什么要对他下手呢
Why would I move on him?
他答应在把股份卖给资本集团之后
He agreed to give me a major chunk of change
分给我其中很大的一份
of an upcoming sale of shares to some equity group.
所以我们没事了
So we were good.
那并不能解释你在巷子里朝他开枪
That doesn't square with you shooting at him in the alley.
那不是我  我发誓
That wasn't me. I swear!
如果不是  那是谁
If it wasn't you, then who was it?
我不知道
I don't know.
希德打电话给我
Sid called me and told me
说转让给我的节目股份文件准备好了
the paperwork for my stake in the show was ready.
但他不肯签字
But he wouldn't sign off
除非我先给他一样东西
unless I brought him something.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我就陪你玩
I'll play along.
希德让你给他带什么
What did Sid want you to bring?
一把未注册的枪
An unregistered gun.
希德要枪干什么
Why would Sid want a gun?
等等  让我猜猜  他没告诉你吧
Wait, no. Let me guess. He didn't tell you.
他真的没告诉我
It's true!
他只说让我11点半在那个小巷等他
He just told me to meet him near that alley
我就去了
11:30, so I did.
我给了他一把点38手枪
I gave him a .38 special,
他跟我说我今天早上
and he told me I could pick up
就可以去取签好字的文件了
the signed papers in the morning.
然后他让我远走高飞
And then he told me I should take a hike.
但你没这么做
But you didn't.
他要了一把枪
Well... a man asks for a gun,
他这是要趟浑水
he's looking to dance with danger.
我觉得我应该保护我的投资
I thought it wise to protect my investment.
你是说你留在那
So you're saying that you stuck around
-就为了看会发生什么事  -是的
- just to see what would happen. - Yep.
我看到希德穿过小巷躲进了一个门廊
Saw Sid go down the alley and hide in a doorway.
20分钟过去
20 minutes go by,
一个带面具的人出现了
and some dude in a mask shows up.
打开垃圾箱拿出一个绿色背包
Opens the dumpster, pulls out a green duffel bag.
背包里是什么
And what was in the duffel bag?
我怎么知道
Hell if I know.
这时希德拿着枪跳了出来  大声叫着
But that's when Sid jumps out with the gun, screaming,
你要的已经给你了  她在哪
"You got what you wanted! Now where is she?"
她是谁
Who is "She"?
我不知道
I have no idea.
但那个戴面具的人制住了希德
But the masked man got the drop on Sid.
他们扭打着去抢枪  然后砰砰砰
They wrestled for the gun, and then, pop, pop, pop!
枪响了
Shots go off in the air!
如果你想保护你的投资
You know what? If you were protecting your investment,
那你为什么没帮他
then why didn't you help him out?
希德跑了呀
Well, Sid ran off.
那个戴面具的人也没追他
And the guy in the mask wasn't giving chase,
所以我想  我还在假释期呢
So I figured, well, I'm on parole.
得在警察来之前赶紧跑
I need to bug out before the cops show up.
你这是旁观
And that's all you did?
我开车去了希德家看看能不能截住他
I drove to Sid's building to see if I could catch him
质问他到底把我卷进了什么事
and ask him what the hell he got me into.
但他一直没出现
But he never showed up.
紧接着  我就听说他死了
Next thing I know, he's dead.
我觉得他说的是实话
I think he's telling the truth.
希德公寓外的监控录像
Security video outside of Sid's apartment
拍到范·赞特在他车里
shows Van Zant waiting out front
从12点30到凌晨3点30一直等在那
in his car from 12:30 A.M. to 3:30 in the morning.
那里和摄影棚离得远着呢
That's on the other side of town from the studio.
范·赞特不可能作案
Yeah, Van Zant couldn't have done it.
你搜查的那个垃圾箱
Okay, that dumpster that you searched --
里面有背包吗
There was no duffel bag?
戴面具的人拿走了包
The guy in the mask must have taken it,
说明那个包是希德
which means that Sid must have been the guy
放那里的
who dropped it off.
希德说的交易肯定是指这个
This has to be the deal that Sid was talking about,
那个背包装的是赎金
and that duffel bag was the payoff.
绝对没错
Yeah, it sure was.
我和业务经理谈了
I spoke with the business manager.
他刚发现在他被杀当天
He just discovered that on the day he was murdered,
-希德取了一大笔钱  -多少
- Sid made a huge bank withdrawal. - How huge?
400万无序美钞
$4 million in nonsequential bills.
无序美钞
Nonsequential bills?
各位  这是起出岔的绑架案
You guys, this was a ransom gone wrong.
所以希德才会问  她在哪
That's why Sid asked, "Where is she?"
-他认识的某个女人被绑架了  -谁呢
- Some woman is his life was kidnapped. - Yeah, but who?
那就是我们要查出的
That's what we got to find out.
因为绑架她的人很可能就是凶手
'cause whoever took her might be our killer.
《今晚周六夜》的演员和工作人员
The cast and the crew of "Saturday night tonight"
都在摄影棚
are all at the studio.
无人失踪
No one is missing.
我们找到了希德的妻子  家人
So we've covered Sid's wife, his family,
朋友  同事
his friends, and now his job.
大家都没事
Everyone's accounted for.
事实上  不是所有人
Uh, actually, not everyone.
伊芙琳·罗斯  希德的第一任妻子
Evelyn Ross, Sid's first wife.
她失踪了吗
She's missing?
我询问了希德的儿子
Well, I followed up with Sid's son,
他说她一直没回电话
and he said that she hadn't returned
所以我去问了她的门卫
any of his phone calls, so I spoke with her doorman.
门卫说伊芙琳两天前去晨跑后
Said that Evelyn went on her usual 6:00 A.M. run
就再也没回来
two days ago, and he hasn't seen her since.
她肯定就是被绑者
She's got to be our kidnap vic.
没错  而且我定位了她的手机
Yes, and I was able to ping her cell phone.
-没错而且  -我没有
- "Yes, and..." - I wasn't doing that.
-你刚说完  -警员发现手机
- No, you did it just now. - Anyway, uniforms found the phone
被扔在布朗克斯一家酒馆旁的垃圾箱
dumped in a trash can near a bodega in the Bronx,
很可能是绑架者扔的
probably tossed there by her kidnapper.
有点不对劲
Somethins not right here.
首先被害人的行为就不对劲
Starting with our victim's behavior.
假设你是希德  你前妻被绑架了
You're Sid. Your ex-wife gets kidnapped.
在小巷中救回她的计划也失败了
The deal in the alley to get her back goes south.
这种情况下  你为什么还不找警察
At that point, why wouldn't you go to the police?
为什么要回你的办公室去
Why do you go back to your office?
我再去趟希德的办公室  看有什么发现
I'll circle back with Sid's office, see what I can find out.
警员刚送来了伊芙琳的手机
Yo, unis just arrived with Evelyn's phone.
这是伊芙琳的云账户
This is Evelyn's cloud account.
和她的手机是同步的
It's synched to her cell phone.
跑步地图  是那个健身应用
Map My Jog. That's a fitness app.
打开好吗
Can you click on it?
看来一直在运行
Looks like it's been running this whole time.
我见过这款应用
I've seen this app before.
用卫星定位系统计算
They use G.P.S. to calculate
跑步者的跑步距离和速度
a jogger's distance and pace
最重要的是还有跑步路线
and most importantly, their route.
重播一次伊芙琳的最后一次跑步路线好吗
Can you replay Evelyn's last path?
这是她离开了公寓
That's her leaving her building.
她跑向了公园
Okay, so she jogged to the park.
等等  这是她被绑架的时候吧
Wait. Is this when she got kidnapped?
肯定是  她的速度是每小时30英里
It's got to be. She's moving at 30 miles an hour.
-她肯定在车上  -没错
- She had to have been in a vehicle. - Yeah.
可以快进一下看看终点在哪里吗
Can you fast-forward so that we can see where she ended up?
她被带去了布朗克斯区
So she was taken up to the Bronx.
看来她停在了这座建筑物里
Okay, looks like she stopped at this building.
伊芙琳可能还在里面
Evelyn might still be in that building.
那是什么地方
What do we know about that place?
-不知道  我们去查  -好的
- I don't know. We'll find out. - Okay.
莱恩  希德的办公室有发现吗
Hey, Ryan, you find anything in Sid's office?
没有  只有些文件和表格
No, just paperwork and spreadsheets.
没什么和绑架有关的吗
So nothing that speaks to a possible kidnapping?
都是很直白的东西  但我会带回来
Pretty straightforward stuff, but I'll bring it in
我们再细细梳理一遍
so we can go through it with a fine-tooth comb.
贝克特  有发现
Beckett, we got something.
莱恩  我得挂了
Okay, Ryan, I got to go.
伊芙琳被带去的建筑
That building where Evelyn was taken
是个废弃仓库
is an abandoned warehouse.
这是个藏人质的最佳地点
It's the ideal location to hold someone hostage.
纽约警局
N.Y.P.D.!
上  上  上
Go, go, go!
那里  在那里
There. Over there.
在这边  踹开
Over here! Kick it.
伊芙琳
Evelyn?
我们是警察  你现在安全了
We're the police. You're safe now.
天呐
Oh, god...
我只是停下来伸展一下
I just had stopped to stretch,
下一秒  就有一块破布
and the next thing I knew, there was a rag
捂住了我的嘴巴  然后
over my mouth, and...
我再醒来时  就在仓库里了
Uh, when I came to, I was in that warehouse.
有没有哪个时刻  你看见了
At any point in time, did you get a look
绑架者的脸
at your kidnapper's face?
他一直带着面具
He always wore a mask.
像是个滑雪面具  但很有光泽
It was like a ski mask, but shiny,
中间有道银色的锯齿
with a silver zigzag up the middle
还有个金色的头饰带
and...a gold headband.
金色的头饰带  你确定吗
A gold headband? Are you sure about that?
我很确定那就是个头饰带
I'm pretty sure that's what it was.
他的衣着呢
And, uh, how about his clothes?
你记得他的衣着有什么特别的吗
Do you remember anything distinctive about them?
不记得
No.
但是  他戴着戒指
But...he wore a ring.
他右手上戴着一枚红银相间的图章戒指
A red and silver signet ring on his right hand.
我记得
I remember that.
伊芙琳  再回到面具
Evelyn, back to the mask --
它跟这个面具相似吗
did it look anything like this?
是的  一模一样
Yes, exactly like that.
这是《今晚周六夜》节目里的吗
Is that from "Saturday Night Tonight"?
这个出自他们两年前一个不怎么出名的段子
It's from an obscure sketch they did two years ago
名叫《墨西哥摔角早茶自助》
called "Lucha Libre Brunch Buffet."
就是说绑架者可以进入
So our kidnapper had access
演播室的道具服装室
to the props and wardrobe room at the studio.
这是监守自盗
This was an inside job.
香蕉三明治  怎么个意思
What do you mean, a banana sandwich?
卡莉  卡莉·蕾
Carly! Carly Rae --
卡莉·蕾·吉普森  我叫里克
Carly Rae Jepsen! I'm Rick. I'm Rick.
这是凯特  我们都很崇拜你
I'm -- uh, this is Kate. We're huge fans.
谢谢  这对我来说意义重大
Oh, thanks. That means a lot to me.
很高兴认识你  卡塞尔  我们真的得
So nice to meet you. Um, Castle, we really need to --
是的  卡莉  一个小问题  那首歌
Yeah, Carly, quick question -- that one song,
《有空叩我》  你的第一句歌词
Um, "Call Me Maybe," What did you mean by the lyric --
-是什么意思  -卡莉  还有两分钟
- it's in the first... - Carly, two minutes.
对不起  我得上台唱歌了
Oh, I'm so sorry. I have to go perform this song.
没事  没事
Oh, that -- that's cool.
我们得去破谋杀案了  所以
We gotta go solve a murder, so...
-好了  -很高兴认识你  再见
- Okay. Okay. - Nice to meet you. Bye.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
有人最近借了这些面具中的一个
Someone recently checked out one of these masks,
-我们得知道是谁  -现在吗
- and we need to know who. - Now?
我们正在直播
We're in the middle of a live show.
它在《墨西哥摔角早茶自助》里用过
It was from the "Lucha Libre Brunch Buffet" sketch.
是啊  那个段子糟透了
Yeah, that sketch sucked.
我们好多年没用过那些面具了
We haven't used those masks in years.
有出借登记记录吗
Well, is there a record of someone signing it out?
可能没有  但我可以查查
Probably not, but I can check.
能给我五分钟吗
Can you give me like five minutes?
好的  我们待会回来
Okay. We'll be back.
真相就快水落石出了
We are so close.
是啊  但谁如此肆无忌惮
Yeah, but who would be so brazen --
或者如此天真地戴着节目里的面具
or so naive -- as to use a mask from the show
去实施绑架呢
to perpetrate a kidnapping?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
有请卡莉·蕾·吉普森
performing her hit single,
带来她的火热单曲《君乃我至爱》
"I Really Like you," Carly Rae Jepsen.
这首歌送给你  希德
This is for you, Sid.
*我几欲悬崖勒马*
*I really wanna stop*
*又不愿浅尝辄止*
*But I just got the taste for it*
*我欲与君相约  共赴月之传奇*
*I feel like I could fly with the boy on the moon*
*愿君执我之手*
*So, honey, hold my hand*
*我自望眼欲穿*
*You like making me wait for it*
*欲仙欲死只为  走近君之屋室*
*I feel I could die walking up to the room*
*深夜看电视*
*Late night, watching television*
*因何置于此*
*But how'd we get in this position*
*一切皆太快  我心知非爱*
*It's way too soon, I know this isn't love*
*欲诉与君知*
*But I need to tell you something*
*君乃我*
*I really, really, really, really, really, really*
*至爱*
*Like you*
*妾愿伴君侧  君要妾与否*
*And I want you, do you want me*
*君亦思妾否*
*Do you want me, too*
*君乃我*
*I really, really, really, really, really, really*
*至爱*
*Like you*
*妾愿伴君侧  君要妾与否*
*And I want you, do you want me*
*君亦思妾否*
*Do you want me, too*
*我自知失言*
*Oh, did I say too much*
*只因不见你*
*I'm so in my head*
*我心乱如麻*
*When we're out of touch*
*君乃我*
*I really, really, really, really, really, really*
*至爱*
*Like you*
*妾愿伴君侧  君要妾与否*
*And I want you, do you want me*
跳得不错
Nice moves.
你们想要个好座位吗
Hey, you guys want a better seat?
在预留座位上看表演再精彩不过了
There's nothing like watching the show from house seats.
没关系的
Hey, it's cool.
如果你愿意话可以继续待在这里
You can stay here if you like.
贝克特  看他的戒指
Beckett, check out his ring.
和伊芙琳形容的一样
Just like Evelyn described.
查德  我们给你预留了位置
Hey, Chad, we've got a house seat for you --
就在12分局里  我们走吧
down at the 12th precinct. Let's go.
查德  告诉我们
So, Chad, tell us,
你在《今晚周六夜》做助理多久了
How long have you been a page with "S.N.T."?
很棒的五年  怎么了
Uh, five incredible years. Why?
大部分助理一两年后没有升职
Don't most pages quit if they don't get promoted
就会辞职吧
after a year or two?
对我来说  这值得等待
Uh, for me, it's worth the wait.
任何一天我都可能升职
Any day now.
抱歉  我不相信
Yeah, sorry. I don't buy it.
我认为你等得厌烦了
I think you got tired of waiting,
这么多年后  你想要回报
and after so many years, you wanted payback.
回报  你指的是什么回报
Payback? What do you mean, payback?
我说的是400万美元的那种回报
I'm talking about the $4 million kind.
你绑架了希德的前妻
You kidnapped Sid's ex-wife.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
这个计划挺巧妙的
It was a pretty clever plan.
只有一个小细节
All except for that one tiny detail
你没预见到
that you could not have foreseen --
希德在交钱时与你对峙
Sid confronting you at the money drop.
他认出了你的戒指  是吧
He recognized your ring, didn't he?
那时你意识到你唯一的出路
That was when you realized your only way out
就是杀了他
was to kill him.
你觉得我杀了罗斯先生
You think I killed Mr. Ross?
别装了  我们知道你的所作所为
You can drop the act. We know what you did.
就连伊芙琳也看到了你的戒指
Even Evelyn saw your ring.
这枚戒指是我在SNT纪念品店买的
I bought this ring at the "S.N.T." gift shop.
很多人都有
Lots of people have it.
是啊  但其他人的公寓里
Yeah, except lots of people don't have evidence
可没有证据
in their apartments.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything!
那你倒是解释下为什么警探会在你床下
So then why don't you explain how detectives found
找到一把点38左轮枪和一张墨西哥摔角面具
a .38 revolver and a lucha libre mask under your bed?
一定是邪恶的牙仙放在那里的
Must have been an evil tooth fairy who put it there,
反正不是我
'cause it wasn't me.
求你们相信我  不是我
Please, I-I-I didn't do this.
那么希德被害当晚你在哪里
All right, then where were you the night that Sid was murdered?
-在家  -有人能证实吗
- At home. - Can anyone verify that?
没有
No.
希德是个严厉的混蛋  但他爱他的工作
Sid was a tough S.O.B., but he loved his job,
他的工作是让我们逗美国人民笑
and his job was to get us to make America laugh.
今晚我们通过这种方式向他致敬
And tonight we honor him by doing just that.
查德不可能是凶手  对吧
Chad can't be the killer, can he?
感觉不对劲
Well, it doesn't feel right,
但的确有很多对他不利的证据
but there is an abundance of evidence.
太多了  面具  凶器  戒指
Yeah, it's too abundant -- the mask, the gun, the ring?
太...完美了
It's just too...perfect.
你觉得他被嫁祸了
So, what, you think he was framed?
我觉得另有内情
I think there's more to this story.
有可能凶手想让伊芙琳
You know, it's possible that the killer wanted
看到面具和戒指
Evelyn to see the mask and the ring.
查德是完美的替罪羊
Chad is the perfect fall guy.
如果不是查德  是谁干的呢
Okay, but if Chad didn't do it, then who did?
我可能找到了线索
I...may have a line on that.
我知道希德在办公室看电子表格
I figured out what Sid was doing in his office
是为什么了
with those spreadsheets.
他在查看公司的银行账户
He was going over his corporate bank accounts.
希德在枪口下给劫匪付赎金
Sid went from paying a kidnapper at gunpoint
然后查看公司财务
to checking his corporate financials?
好...奇怪
That's...weird.
不只是这件事奇怪
That's not the only thing that's weird.
看看他涂亮的部分
Check out those expenses he highlighted.
这些奇怪是因为
Oh, these are weird, because...
因为我给开曼群岛的银行打了电话
Because I called the bank in the Cayman Islands.
这些开支都是伪造的
All of those expenses are bogus.
某个能着手希德公司的人在挪用公款
So someone with access at Sid's company was embezzling money.
数额接近400万
Almost $4 million,
跟赎金一样
The exact amount of the ransom.
这就是了
Wait, that's it.
挪用公款的人试图把从希德那偷来的钱
The embezzler was trying to replace the money
补回来
he had stolen from sid.
-我知道凶手是谁了  -我知道凶手是谁了
- I know who the killer is. - I know who the killer is.
赞  不过我得说是我把你领上正路
Nice. In fairness, though, I walked you right through that.
最后一个段子准备好
Places for the final sketch!
Places for the final sketch.
一切还好吗
Hi. I-is everything all right?
是的  事实上  我们有好消息
Yes. In fact, we have some good news.
好极了  节目结束后咱们聊
Great. Let's talk after the show.
演出已经结束了  至少对你来说
Actually, show is already over -- at least for you.
-什么  -别装了  沃格尔先生
- Excuse me? - Drop the act, Mr. Vogel.
我们知道是你杀了希德
We know that you killed Sid.
-这太疯狂了  -并不
- That's insane. - Not really.
考虑到希德公司分批销售
Not considering the partial sale of Sid's company
在即  一旦销售就意味着
was on the horizon, a sale that would mean
公司财务核查
a review of the company's books.
那将揭露你盗用400万公司公款
Which would expose the $4 million that you embezzled.
什么  你们发疯了吗
What?! Are you out of your mind?
没有  发疯的是你
No, but you must have been.
面对恶行被揭穿的现实
Faced with the inevitability of being caught,
你得有所行动
you had to do something,
于是你绑架伊芙琳  索要赎金
so you kidnapped and ransomed Evelyn
以便偿还你盗用的钱款
in order to "reimburse" the money you'd stolen.
一大包现金更容易存入
A duffel bag full of cash would be easy to deposit
公司在开曼群岛的银行
in the company's Cayman Island bank,
没人会提出质疑
where no questions are asked.
那之后  你只需
And after that, all you'd have to do
伪造银行对账单
is falsify a few bank statements,
你就高枕无忧了
and you'd be in the clear.
你们怎么敢这样  太扯了
How dare you. This is absurd!
我们追踪的钱款  基恩
We followed the money, Gene.
你从公司取出400万  投资创业公司
You siphoned the $4 million to invest in a startup company.
当公司破产
And when that company went belly-up,
你拿不回你的钱
you could not get your money back.
希德定是在碰头地点认出了你
Sid must have recognized you at the drop,
但在那之后  他没有与你对质  直到他发现
but he didn't confront you until after he discovered
伪造的开支
the faked expenses.
所以你就杀了他
So you killed him?
基恩  你怎么能这样做
Gene, how could you?
不  这都是无凭证的指控
No! These are -- these are baseless accusations.
-他们什么证实不了  -事实上  我们可以
- They can't prove anything. - Actually, we can.
我们查了你的财务  发现
We went through your financials and found
数百万来自希德公司的未申报存款
millions in undeclared deposits from Sid's company.
顺便提一句
Oh, by the way, nice touch
戴面具  戴查德的SNT戒指够绝
wearing the mask and "S.N.T." ring that Chad has.
你栽赃陷害的唯一破绽是
Only problem with your frame job --
你当天下午投放栽赃物时
you were witnessed hanging around
有人看到你在他的公寓外
outside his apartment this afternoon when you planted them.
基恩·沃格尔  你因...
Gene Vogel, you're under arrest for --
模特女警探遇到麻烦  高跟断了
Model cop down! I broke a heel!
基恩·沃格尔  你因绑架和谋杀
Gene Vogel, you're under arrest for kidnapping
而被捕
and murder!
贝克特  今晚节目上的缉捕帅爆了
Beckett, that was a badass takedown tonight on that show.
强势而性感
It was strong, yet...sexy.
是的  贝克特  镜头爱死你了
Yeah, Beckett, the camera really loves you.
你们俩都给我闭嘴
You guys, shut up, both of you.
我呢  伙计们  上镜效果如何
What about me, guys? How did I look?
你还是老实写作吧
Like you should stick to writing.
我也这样认为
Yeah, I think so.
咱家只有一位明星  孩子
There's only one star in this family, kiddo.
母上  预演如何
Mother, how was your preview performance?
你自己看吧
Well, check out, the, uh,
-所谓推特宇宙  -好
- the twittervese, as they say. - All righty.
玛莎·罗杰斯美妙绝伦
"Martha Rodgers is a revelation."
玛莎·罗杰斯献出大师级演出
"Martha Rodgers gives a masterful performance."
她的表演证实舞台剧仍是重要的艺术形式
"A display of why theater is still a relevant art form."
玛莎·罗杰斯赞爆了
"Martha Rodgers is amaze-balls."
这个词
Yeah, that -- about that --
赞爆了是好话吗  因为我...
Is that "Amaze-balls" a good thing, because...
是的  恭喜
It sure is. Congratulations.
-恭喜  -太好了  我们可以庆祝了
- Congratulations. - Okay, oh, great. Then we can celebrate.
我带了香槟
I brought some champagne for everybody!
你来打开吧  有杯子吗
If you'll open it. Do we have some glasses?
玛莎  我们这不怎么庆祝
Well, we don't do a lot of entertaining here, Martha,
但有这个
But ta-da!
好勒  这个可以  谢谢
Here you go. That'll work. Thank you.
-谢谢  -我来
- Thank you. - May I?
好极了  谢谢  莱恩警探
Perfect. Thank you, Detective Ryan.
-谢谢  -女士们先生们  敬我赞爆的老妈
- Thank you. - Ladies and gentlemen, to my amaze-balls mother.
百老汇最棒的第二幕
The best second act on Broadway.
干杯
Cheers.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.